[
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "How many legs does a spider have?",
    "answers": ["Six", "Eight", "Four", "Two"],
    "correct": "Eight"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What’s the name of a place you go to see lots of animals?",
    "answers": ["Park", "School", "Bus", "Zoo"],
    "correct": "zoo"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What type of fish is Nemo?",
    "answers": ["Goldfish", "Clownfish", "Blobfish", "Bluefish"],
    "correct": "Clownfish"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What do caterpillars turn into?",
    "answers": ["Tigers", "Monsters", "Butterflies", "Zebras"],
    "correct": "Butterflies"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "How many pairs of wings do bees have?",
    "answers": ["Eleven", "Four", "Two", "One"],
    "correct": "Two"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What is a doe?",
    "answers": ["What pizza is made of", "Female deer", "Space behind a frogs knees", "Bear toes"],
    "correct": "Female deer"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What is a group of lions called?",
    "answers": ["a pack", "a liars", "a beast", "a pride"],
    "correct": "a pride"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What’s the first thing a caterpillar usually eats after it’s born?",
    "answers": ["other bugs", "grass", "Cheerios", "it's own eggshell"],
    "correct": "its own eggshell"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "The trumpeter swan—North America’s largest waterfowl—weighs about how many pounds?",
    "answers": ["30", "10", "50", "70"],
    "correct": "30"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "Which of the following animals is not nocturnal?",
    "answers": ["Skunk", "Leopard", "Tiger", "Sheep"],
    "correct": "Sheep"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "Walruses can eat about how many clams in one day?",
    "answers": ["5,000", "10,000", "12,000", "16,000"],
    "correct": "5,000"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "What is a baby rabbit called?",
    "answers": ["Doe", "Buck", "Kit", "Hare"],
    "correct": "Kit"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "How many koalas stacked on top of one another does it take to reach the height of a male giraffe—the world’s tallest land animal?",
    "answers": ["7","2", "4", "50"],
    "correct": "7"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "An ant says, “Danger ahead!” by doing what?",
    "answers": ["squealing", "running toward water", "rolling on its back", "oozing chemicals"],
    "correct": "oozing chemicals"
  },
  {
    "category": "animals",
    "question":
      "Which of the following is not a type of penguin?",
    "answers": ["waterland","emperor", "chinstrap", "macaroni"],
    "correct": "waterland"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
     "What is the bright glow around the “head” of a comet called?",
    "answers": ["Ring", "Coma", "Halo", "Crown"],
    "correct": "Coma"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
      "Which of the following did people used to think seeing a comet signified?",
    "answers": ["Disaster", "Disease", "Death", "All the above"],
    "correct": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
      "What is the name of the famous comet that can be seen from Earth about every 75 years?",
    "answers": ["Hale-Bopp", "Shoemaker-Levy 9", "Halley’s Comet", "Pluto"],
    "correct": "Halley’s Comet"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
      "How many tails does a comet have?",
    "answers": ["Most have 2", "Only 1", "Roughly 3", "At least 5" ],
    "correct": "Most have 2"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
      "What is the name of a well known meteor shower that peaks in August each year?",
    "answers": ["Persieds","Pleiades", "Summer Shower", "Orion"],
    "correct": "Perseids"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
      "What is the scientific name for a shooting star?",
    "answers": ["Comet", "Asteroid", "Falling star", "Meteor"],
    "correct": "Meteor"
  },
  {
    "category": "space",
    "question":
      "What is the name of a well known meteor shower that peaks each November?",
    "answers": ["Leonids", "Linus", "Northern Lights", "Winter Shower"],
    "correct": "Leonids"   
  },

  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
      "Which ocean is off the California coast?",
    "answers": ["Atlantic", "Indian", "Pacific", "Red sea"],
    "correct": "Pacific"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
      "What is something you hit with a hammer?",
    "answers": ["Screw", "Rubberband", "Nail", "Wrench"],
    "correct": "Nail"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
     "What colors are the stars on the American flag?",
    "answers": ["Red", "Orange", "Blue", "White"],
    "correct": "White"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
     "Who was the first president of the united states?",
    "answers": ["Thomas Edison", "George Washington", "Abraham Lincoln", "Richard Nixon"],
    "correct": "George Washington"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
     "The Blue part of a map represents what?",
    "answers": ["Land", "Stars", "Water", "People"],
    "correct": "Water"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
     "Where does the president of the united states live while in office?",
    "answers": ["New York", "Buckingham Palace", "The White house", "Federal reserve"],
    "correct": "The White house"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
        "What fruit do kids traditionally give to teachers?",
    "answers": ["Pizza", "Orange", "Apple", "iPod"],
    "correct": "Apple"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
        "What do you use to write on a blackboard?",
    "answers": ["Grapes", "Sharpie", "Crayon", "Chalk"],
    "correct": "Chalk"
  }, 
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
        " On which holiday do you go trick-or-treating?",
    "answers": ["Columbus Day", "Christmas", "Valentine's Day", "Halloween"],
    "correct": "Halloween"
  },
  {
    "category": "social studies",
    "question":
        "Where is the Great Pyramid of Giza?",
    "answers": ["Egypt", "Netherlands", "New Zealand", "New York"],
    "correct": "Egypt"
  },
  {
    "category": "money",
    "question":
        "How many cents is a quarter worth?",
    "answers": ["fifteen", "one houndered", "ten", "twenty five"],
    "correct": "twenty five"
  },
  {
    "category": "money",
    "question":
        "How many pennies equal 1 dollar? ",
    "answers": ["one houndred", "five houndred", "five", "twenty"],
    "correct": "one houndred"
  },
  {
    "category": "money",
    "question":
        "How many cents are in 2 quarters?",
    "answers": ["twenty", "two houndred", "fifty", "seventy five"],
    "correct": "fifty"
  },
  {
    "category": "money",
    "question":
        "You have 6 coins that equal 19 cents, which coins and how many do you have?",
    "answers": ["4 pennies", "1 Dime, and 1 Nickel", "1 Dime, 1 Nickel & 4 Pennies", "quarter"],
    "correct": "1 Dime, 1 Nickel & 4 Pennies"
  },
  {
    "category": "money",
    "question":
        "You have seven coins that equal 1.16 cents, which coins and how many do you have?",
    "answers": ["5 quarters", "2 Dimes, and 1 Penny", "1 Dime, 1 Nickel & 4 Pennies", "10 Dimes"],
    "correct": " 4 Quarters, 1 Dime, 1 Nickel & 1 Penny"
  },
  {
    "category": "money",
    "question":
        "You went to the store with $2.30 cents.  You want to buy as many candy bars as you can.  Each candy car is on sale for 35 cents. How many candy bars can you afford?",
    "answers": ["6 candy bars", "1 candy bar", "no candy bars", "a twizler"],
    "correct": "6 candy cars"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "Lures, reels, rods, hooks, baits and nets are common equipment used in what food gathering method?",
    "answers": ["swimming", "hunting", "fishing", "napping"],
    "correct": "fishing"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "Dairy products are made from what common liquid?",
    "answers": ["milk", "koolaid", "water", "chocolate milk"],
    "correct": "milk"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "What is the popular food used to carve jack-o-lanterns during Halloween?",
    "answers": ["apples", "chickens", "oranges", "pumpkins"],
    "correct": "pumpkins"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "What color are kiwis on the inside?",
    "answers": ["purple", "pink", "green", "orange"],
    "correct": "green"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "What fruit is not grown on a tree? Lemons, apples, strawberries, or bananas? ",
    "answers": ["lemons", "apples", "banana", "strawberries"],
    "correct": "strawberries"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "What food is used as the base of guacamole?",
    "answers": ["avocado", "spinach", "pudding", "salsa"],
    "correct": "avocado"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "Which is not a fruit?",
    "answers": ["apple", "tomato", "grape", "carrot"],
    "correct": "carrot"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "Which is not dairy?",
    "answers": ["milk", "goat cheese", "butter", "guacamole"],
    "correct": "guacamole"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "What are dried grapes called?",
    "answers": ["raisins", "sultanas", "currants", "all the above"],
    "correct": "all the above"
  },
  {
    "category": "food",
    "question":
        "Which is the only fruit with seeds on the outer skin?",
    "answers": ["blueberries", "strawberries", "oranges", "bananas"],
    "correct": "strawberries"
  }
]
